<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="//assets/xslt/atom.xslt" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="//assets/css/atom.css" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<id>http://localhost:4000//</id>
	<title>NeCOL</title>
	<updated>2019-05-28T10:26:54-04:00</updated>

	<subtitle>This website presents the main outcomes of &lt;strong&gt;NeCOL project&lt;/strong&gt; under the &lt;strong&gt;Marie Sklodowska-Curie grant agreement No 799078&lt;/strong&gt;.</subtitle>

	
		
		<author>
			
				<name>Jamal Toutouh</name>
			
			
				<email>toutouh@mit.edu</email>
			
			
				<uri>http://www.jamal.es/</uri>
			
		</author>
	

	<link href="http://localhost:4000//atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link href="http://localhost:4000//" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />

	<generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator>

	
		<entry>
			<id>http://localhost:4000//publications/rcc-innovative_teaching/</id>
			<title>Presenting our work about innovative teaching at Harvard</title>
			<link href="http://localhost:4000//publications/rcc-innovative_teaching/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Presenting our work about innovative teaching at Harvard" />
			<updated>2019-05-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>Jamal Toutouh</name>
					
					
						<email>toutouh@mit.edu</email>
					
					
						<uri>http://www.jamal.es/</uri>
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>We presented our work entitled Gamification to Mitigate Demotivation and Unevenness in Engineering Courses. during the International Annual Conference in Innovative Teaching: Renovating the University for Future Generations (IACIT@RCC). </summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000//publications/rcc-innovative_teaching/">&lt;p&gt;Our work about applying &lt;em&gt;Gamification&lt;/em&gt; in our lectures to motivate our Engineering students was accepted to be presented during the &lt;strong&gt;International Annual Conference in Innovative Teaching: Renovating the University for Future Generations (IACIT@RCC)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://rcc.harvard.edu/event/IACIT&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[ACIT@RCC]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which took place at RCC–Harvard on May 16-17, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main idea behind our presentation was to share our experience when teaching  Engineering degrees, in which we apply gamification to address two main issues: the students lack of motivation and the &lt;em&gt;large differences in the students back-ground and skills&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamaltoutouh.github.io/downloads/Gamification_RCC2019.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Download the presentation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;abstract-of-our-work&quot;&gt;Abstract of our work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lecturers have to face two main difficulties when teaching Engineering degrees: the students &lt;strong&gt;lack of motivation&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;large differences in the students back-ground and skills&lt;/em&gt;. An innovative teaching project &lt;strong&gt;(PIE17-122)&lt;/strong&gt; funded by the University of Malaga proposes the use of &lt;strong&gt;gamification&lt;/strong&gt; as a way to mitigate such issues by converting the learning process into a funny experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its main objectives are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;increasing the students motivation&lt;/strong&gt; by promoting healthy competition,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;improving cooperation&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;interpersonal relationships&lt;/strong&gt; while seekinga balance among the groups,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fostering the loyalty&lt;/strong&gt; of the students to the subject.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The methodology applied consists of three phases: preparation, execution, and monitoring. During preparation, we design knowledge tests, games, and surveys. The execution phase consists in performing the games and surveys. The monitoring phase includes several procedures to asses the evolution of students cognitive skills, their level of motivation, and the degree of learning. The tasks performed during the monitoring phase and the feedback of the students allow the lecturers to better adapt the games and the content of the lessons to the reale volution of the students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main conclusions are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;an improvement in the students &lt;strong&gt;engagement&lt;/strong&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the students &lt;strong&gt;prefer games that involve ICT platforms&lt;/strong&gt; (such as, Kahoot or Socrative),&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the competitiveness among groups increases when the games have &lt;strong&gt;any kind of prize&lt;/strong&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;and applying gamification &lt;strong&gt;is not as simple as introducing games&lt;/strong&gt; in the courses, since a bad design of the games can lead to a loss of interest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>

			
				<category term="publications" />
			
			
				<category term="publication" />
			
				<category term="innovative teaching" />
			
				<category term="jamal" />
			
				<category term="gamification" />
			

			<published>2019-05-28T00:00:00-04:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>http://localhost:4000//publications/swm-journal-accepted/</id>
			<title>Smart waste management by using integer programming</title>
			<link href="http://localhost:4000//publications/swm-journal-accepted/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Smart waste management by using integer programming" />
			<updated>2019-05-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>Jamal Toutouh</name>
					
					
						<email>toutouh@mit.edu</email>
					
					
						<uri>http://www.jamal.es/</uri>
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Our work applying integer programming to address the smart location of waste collection points (bins) has been accepted to be published in &lt;emph&gt;Revista de Ingeniería&lt;/emph&gt; journal</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000//publications/swm-journal-accepted/">&lt;p&gt;In this work, we have addressed the location of bins in two real cities (&lt;strong&gt;Montevideo&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Buenos Aires&lt;/strong&gt;) as an optimization problem. The idea is to provide an efficient waste management system that provides the best quality-of-service possible, while minimizing the budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have defined the problem and we have addressed it by using exact optimization methods &lt;strong&gt;integer programming&lt;/strong&gt; and a greedy algorithm based on &lt;strong&gt;PageRank&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The full paper can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://aprendeenlinea.udea.edu.co/revistas/index.php/ingenieria/article/view/335926&quot; title=&quot;FULL PAPER&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-bi-objective-integer-programming-model-for-locating-garbage-accumulation-points-a-case-study&quot;&gt;A bi-objective integer programming model for locating garbage accumulation points a case study&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enhancing efficiency in Municipal Solid Waste (MSW) management is crucial for local governments, which are generally in charge of collection, since this activity explains a large proportion of their budgetary expenses. The incorporation of decision support tools can contribute to improve the MSW system, specially by reducing the required investment of funds. This article proposes a mathematical formulation, based on integer programming, to determine the location of garbage accumulation points while minimizing the expenses of the system, i.e., the installment cost of bins and the required number of visits the collection vehicle which is related with the routing cost of the collection. The model was tested in some scenarios of an important Argentinian city that stills has a door-to-door system, including instances with unsorted waste, which is the current situation of the city, and also instances with source classified waste. Although the scenarios with classified waste evidenced to be more challenging for the proposed resolution approach, a set of solutions was provided in all scenarios. These solutions can be used as a starting point for migrating from the current door-to-door system to a community bins system.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>

			
				<category term="publications" />
			
			
				<category term="publication" />
			
				<category term="journal" />
			
				<category term="jamal" />
			
				<category term="smart cities" />
			

			<published>2019-05-05T00:00:00-04:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>http://localhost:4000//publications/gecco-accepted/</id>
			<title>GECCO 2019 Paper Accepted</title>
			<link href="http://localhost:4000//publications/gecco-accepted/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GECCO 2019 Paper Accepted" />
			<updated>2019-04-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>Jamal Toutouh</name>
					
					
						<email>toutouh@mit.edu</email>
					
					
						<uri>http://www.jamal.es/</uri>
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>We have received quite positive feedback from the reviewing process and we will present Mustangs in GECCO 2019.</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000//publications/gecco-accepted/">&lt;p&gt;We are happy to inform that our paper &lt;em&gt;Spatial Evolutionary Generative Adversarial Networks&lt;/em&gt; has been accepted as a FULL PAPER to be presented during &lt;a href=&quot;https://gecco-2019.sigevo.org/&quot; title=&quot;GECCO 2019&quot;&gt;GECCO 2019&lt;/a&gt;. GECCO is one of the most important conferences in the field of evolutionary computation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The full paper can be found &lt;a href=&quot;http://alfagroup.csail.mit.edu/sites/default/files/documents/2019Spatial_Evolutionary_Generative_Adversarial_Networks.pdf&quot; title=&quot;FULL PAPER&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;spatial-evolutionary-generative-adversarial-networks&quot;&gt;Spatial Evolutionary Generative Adversarial Networks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generative adversary networks (GANs) suffer from training pathologies such as instability and mode collapse. These pathologies mainly arise from a lack of diversity in their adversarial interactions. Evolutionary generative adversarial networks apply the principles of evolutionary computation to mitigate these problems. We hybridize two of these approaches that promote training diversity. One, E-GAN, at each batch, injects mutation diversity by training the (replicated) generator with three independent objective functions then selecting the resulting best performing generator for the next batch. The other, Lipizzaner, injects population diversity by training a two-dimensional grid of GANs with a distributed evolutionary algorithm that includes neighbor exchanges of additional training adversaries, performance based selection and population-based hyper-parameter tuning. We propose to combine mutation and population approaches to diversity improvement. We contribute a superior evolutionary GANs training method, Mustangs, that eliminates the single loss function used across Lipizzaner ’s grid. Instead, each training round, a loss function is selected with equiprobability, from among the three E-GAN uses. Experimental analyses on a standard benchmark, MNIST, demonstrate that Mustangs provides a statistically faster training method resulting in more accurate networks.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>

			
				<category term="publications" />
			
			
				<category term="publication" />
			
				<category term="gecco" />
			
				<category term="jamal" />
			
				<category term="gan" />
			

			<published>2019-04-11T00:00:00-04:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>http://localhost:4000//publications/gecco-submitted/</id>
			<title>Paper Submitted to GECCO</title>
			<link href="http://localhost:4000//publications/gecco-submitted/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Paper Submitted to GECCO" />
			<updated>2019-02-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>Jamal Toutouh</name>
					
					
						<email>toutouh@mit.edu</email>
					
					
						<uri>http://www.jamal.es/</uri>
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>We have finished writing a nice paper about fosterring diversity in coevolutionary algorithms to train GANs.</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000//publications/gecco-submitted/">&lt;p&gt;We are glad to inform that we have been able to prepare and show some interesting results about our research in fostering diversity when training genertive adversarial networks applying a coevolutionary mehtod. In this case, we have increased the diversity by applying different mutation operators (loss functions) during the trainig process. The proposed framework is named &lt;strong&gt;Mustangs&lt;/strong&gt; and the paper is entitled &lt;em&gt;Spatial Evolutionary Generative Adversarial Networks&lt;/em&gt;. We will be really happy if we are able to present the paper during &lt;a href=&quot;https://gecco-2019.sigevo.org/&quot; title=&quot;GECCO 2019&quot;&gt;GECCO 2019&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;spatial-evolutionary-generative-adversarial-networks&quot;&gt;Spatial Evolutionary Generative Adversarial Networks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generative adversary networks (GANs) suffer from training pathologies such as instability and mode collapse. These pathologies mainly arise from a lack of diversity in their adversarial interactions. Evolutionary generative adversarial networks apply the principles of evolutionary computation to mitigate these problems. We hybridize two of these approaches that promote training diversity. One, E-GAN, at each batch, injects mutation diversity by training the (replicated) generator with three independent objective functions then selecting the resulting best performing generator for the next batch. The other, Lipizzaner, injects population diversity by training a two-dimensional grid of GANs with a distributed evolutionary algorithm that includes neighbor exchanges of additional training adversaries, performance based selection and population-based hyper-parameter tuning. We propose to combine mutation and population approaches to diversity improvement. We contribute a superior evolutionary GANs training method, Mustangs, that eliminates the single loss function used across Lipizzaner ’s grid. Instead, each training round, a loss function is selected with equiprobability, from among the three E-GAN uses. Experimental analyses on a standard benchmark, MNIST, demonstrate that Mustangs provides a statistically faster training method resulting in more accurate networks.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>

			
				<category term="publications" />
			
			
				<category term="publication" />
			
				<category term="gecco" />
			
				<category term="jamal" />
			
				<category term="gan" />
			

			<published>2019-02-06T00:00:00-05:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>http://localhost:4000//general/launched/</id>
			<title>NeCOL Project Website Launched</title>
			<link href="http://localhost:4000//general/launched/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NeCOL Project Website Launched" />
			<updated>2018-09-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>Jamal Toutouh</name>
					
					
						<email>toutouh@mit.edu</email>
					
					
						<uri>http://www.jamal.es/</uri>
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>NeCOL is becoming a reality and we are ready to present here most of the outcomes of this project.</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000//general/launched/">&lt;p&gt;NeCOL is a decir quien financia, las fechas, etc. y el tipo de cosas que vamos a publicar.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="general" />
			
			
				<category term="website" />
			
				<category term="content" />
			
				<category term="jamal" />
			
				<category term="communication" />
			

			<published>2018-09-15T00:00:00-04:00</published>
		</entry>
	
</feed>